<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Tom Preston-Werner</title>
 <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/"/>
 <updated>2010-12-13T22:36:45+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Tom Preston-Werner</name>
   <email>tom@mojombo.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Visual Lyrics</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/visual-lyrics.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/visual-lyrics</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Visual Lyrics&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Visual Lyrics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synesthesia is a really interesting neuronal condition, where different sensations are mixed together and thus some people see colors while listening to sounds or have a different taste while seeing various things. We wanted to re-create this experience based on a song that we like. Thus, we choose a song and depending on it&amp;#8217;s lyrics, there is a re-creation of the song with images and also we can see the cover of the album the song belongs to, made out of these images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/visuallyrics/web.png&quot; title=&quot;Web&quot; alt=&quot;Web&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/visuallyrics/generatedcover.png&quot; title=&quot;Generated cover&quot; alt=&quot;Generated cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was made in less than a day within the context of the Barcelona Music hack day using the following APIs / techonologies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;musiXmatch &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;last fm &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Flickr &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;API&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;PHP&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>uBotherMe</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/uBotherMe.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/uBotherMe</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;uBotherMe&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; uBotherMe&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this hack, we wanted the user of Android to loose control of an alarm clock. So, the alarm clock is controlled trough a webpage, where the user&amp;#8217;s friends can set the alarm with a custom-generated voice message or SoundCloud music link.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sketchyplane</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/sketchyplane.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/sketchyplane</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Sketchyplane&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; SketchyPlane&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sketchy plane is a game where you take the role of a paper airplane or better to say the wind that makes it move! So we can just say that we become something similar to a God of wind :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to control the paper airplaine trying to avoid the birds that come from the top of the screen using something different than a keyboard or a mouse. So why not playing with the air? :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/12589878&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/12589878&quot;&gt;Sketchy Plane&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/victordiaz&quot;&gt;Victor Diaz&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rhythm box</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/rhythm-box.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/rhythm-box</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Rhythm box&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Rhythmbox&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rhythm box is a new generation of percussion instrument that allows the user play different percussion kits, record sequences and modify them using different gestures. It has been designed to have haptic feedback inherited directly from the box properties and visual feedback through the use of light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- we have been working on the construction of a new musical 
instrument focused on percussion. Our approach was making a musical box that could be actually playable and enjoyed by the users since the very beginning, so we went a bit further than just a proof of concept, having a working prototype that can already played and almost with 100% of the proposed functionality.  --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- video   --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The instrument itself can be played in two modes separately or together depending on how it want to be played. One mode is pure percussion, were the player can make beats detected by piezo-electric sensors located on the surface of the box and attached to an Arduino board. The second mode allows the user to record loops and modifying the sound according to certain movements detected through a 3-axys accelerometer and a gyroscope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we developed a fast prototype and our budget was not very high, we used recycled components from old boards resistors and diodes, LEDs, cheap piezo sensors, wood and metal. &lt;br /&gt;
The piezo sensors were located on small holes made into the wooden box and covered with metallic &lt;br /&gt;
plates with a thin layer of foam in the middle to absorb the knock. Piezo sensors are really sensitive and &lt;br /&gt;
just with some slight movements some “knock” can be detected. The foam helped us to reduce that false &lt;br /&gt;
knocks and it turned out the best solution we tried.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- imagen   --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The box has three sides forming the shape of an extruded triangle or prism with each side having two &lt;br /&gt;
piezo-electric sensor, therefore the player will always see two sides at the same time with four sensors &lt;br /&gt;
divided in two groups of sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- imagen  --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- that our interface is both separable, in what concerns to the piezos and knocking and 
integrable in the sense of moving the box in the 3d axys.  --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We tried the instrument with certain amount of subjects and we discovered that the box was a bit too big to be played with. Anyhow, the mapping implemented was quite intuitive for the user.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Olebot</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/olebot.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/olebot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;and control course. &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CSIM&lt;/span&gt; Master &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;UPF&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;del&gt;-&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Olebot&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Olebot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Olebot is based on the “dancer” metaphor. The global goal of this project was to create expressive reaction to the music through movement and visual output of the robot as humans would do, always taking into account the embodied limitations of the robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;!-- One of the reasons behind making the robot dance flamenco, was that most of the robots  --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;#8220;intelligence&amp;#8221; of the robot was given using &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;IQR&lt;/span&gt;, a Large Neural Network Simulator software, using biological paradigms. The music was analyzed in real-time looking for the frequency onsets in order to give stimuli to the neural network that consequently made robot react.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The projections used were made using a basic VJ controller implemented as well with neural networks that changed according to the music in a similar way the robot was simulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/14550291&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/14550291&quot;&gt;Olébot - the flamenco robodancer&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/victordiaz&quot;&gt;Victor Diaz&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lumivi</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/lumivi.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/lumivi</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Lumivi&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Lumivi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lumivi consists in a game designed in order to research the effects of stress on performance levels in immersive environments. In this game the subjects had to play following a white tile on the floor of the eXperience Induction Machine (&lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;XIM&lt;/span&gt;) room as it changed its direction of movement as fastest as possible. The gameplay had to be done under normal and stressing conditions such as color and sound factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  
&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/14550291&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/14550291&quot;&gt;Olébot - the flamenco robodancer&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/victordiaz&quot;&gt;Victor Diaz&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hypothesis of the researchers that performance level increases when subjects were exposed &lt;br /&gt;
to stress, failed to be accepted, because the study could not find any difference in performance of &lt;br /&gt;
the subjects with or without stress factors applied. The study discovered, however, that there is a &lt;br /&gt;
strong correlation between performance scores under stress and the affinity to play sports that &lt;br /&gt;
require intense physical activity.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Flower Power</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/flower-power.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/flower-power</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Flower Power&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Flower power&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;!&amp;#8212; In todays world we do not discover new realities, we create them through virtuality therefore the gap between virtuality and reality get smaller and smaller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simulations of reality replace the real and this simulacrum is hyper reality.&lt;/p&gt;
Characteristics:
- The loss of the materiality of objects (virtual realities)
- The explosion of new media technologies
&lt;p&gt;- Hyperreality connects to performance and must be studied as &lt;br /&gt;
	    being reproduced among wide scale audiences (art, websites…)&lt;/p&gt;
The traditional activity of art has been the representation of reality &amp;#8211; manipulating materials to create tangible mirrors of our experience and desire. Now with the mechanisms of the new digital technologies, the artwork can become itself a simulation of reality &amp;#8211; an immaterial digital structure encompassing synthetic spaces which we can literally enter.
&amp;#8212;&amp;gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Augmented Scalextric</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/augmented-scalextric.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/augmented-scalextric</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Augmented Scalextric&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Scalextricity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scalextricity is an augmentation of the original game Scalectrix, a slot car racing game. The car is tracked using a ps3 camera along the circuit extracting location and speed information which are used to sonify the car and modify the video coming from a wireless camera located on top of the car.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Physiology-based control of affective audio-visual database</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/affective-audiovisual-database.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/affective-audiovisual-database</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Physiology-based control of affective audio-visual database&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Physiology-based control of affective audio-visual database&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study of my master thesis was about studying human emotions and create a biofeedback system that varies the affective state of the user using audiovisual stimuli and at the same time modulate the content being showed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This biofeeback system could be used in the following scenarios:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal cinema&lt;br /&gt;
Treatment for disorders such as chronic pain, depression, etc &lt;br /&gt;
Interactive installations &lt;br /&gt;
Narrative modulation in films &lt;br /&gt;
Relaxing device&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Psychogeophotography</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/Psychogeophotography.html"/>
   <updated>2010-06-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/project/Psychogeophotography</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Psychogeophotography&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;meta&quot;&gt;19 May 2009 &amp;#8211; Psychogeophotography&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>about me</title>
   <link href="http://tom.preston-werner.com/bio/bio.html"/>
   <updated>2010-05-10T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://tom.preston-werner.com/bio/bio</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;about me&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  
&lt;a href=&quot;/docs/victor_diaz_english.pdf&quot;&gt; You can grab my CV here! &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello World! My name is Victor Diaz a Spaniard guy who was born in Granada, Spain and now is living in Barcelona. I studied Telecommunication Engineering and recently I finished an Interdisciplinary Master in Cognitive Systems and Interactive Media aka &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CSIM&lt;/span&gt; in the University Pompeu Fabra of Barcelona.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really interested in human emotions, in how the brain works, in data visualizations, new ways of interfacing with computers, photography, experimental cinema, more humanized architecture and really concerned about new ways of education. And even better if everything is seasoned with open source and free culture :) Too many things isn&amp;#8217;t it? It could be but somehow all of them are interconnected :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can find some of the projects I did. They are not too many and not something that can be called amazing but I enjoyed a lot doing them, specially when my friends got involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My biggest passion is to travel, it always remind me that my culture is not the only one in the world and there is many ways of thinking and seeing about the same thing. This is the beauty of this world, an heritage we should keep, and yes I&amp;#8217;m writing this in English and not in my native language, Spanish :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love languages as well and although I do not speak any perfectly I try to do it in English, French, German and Japanese apart from my mother tongue, Spanish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here some places where I have been (by visiting order)!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spain, Portugal, France, England, Ireland, Italy, Japan, Switzerland, Germany, Czech Republic, The Netherlands, Belgium, Morocco, Hungary, Austria, Poland, Slovakia, Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And places where I lived &lt;br /&gt;
Granada, Jaen, Madrid, Barcelona (Spain), Montpellier (France), Bern (Switzerland) and Tokyo (Japan)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>